freeserifsoftware.com 2010-05-13

# FreeSerifSoftware.com - Privacy Statement

Last Updated: 11th Dec 2009 

## Introduction

**FreeSerifSoftware.com** is owned and operated by the Serif group of companies. FreeSerifSoftware is a brand and trading name of the Serif group of companies which includes Serif (Europe) Ltd and Serif Inc.  
Customers in the UK or Europe should be conducting business with Serif (Europe) Ltd. The privacy of personal data you supply in conducting any business with Serif (Europe) will be governed by this _Privacy Policy_.   
Customers in North America and non-European countries should be conducting business with Serif Inc. The privacy of personal data you supply in conducting any business with Serif Inc will be governed by this _Privacy Policy._

FreeSerifSoftware is a trading name of Serif (Europe) Ltd (“we”, “our” or “us”) registered in England number 2117968 with registered offices at: The Software Centre, 12 Wilford Ind Est, Nottingham NG11 7EP, UK. Telephone: UK - 0845 6740484 Intl.- +44 115 9145472

This Privacy Policy, and any documents it references, inform you how we collect and use the personal information (“Personal Data”) you provide in doing business with FreeSerifSoftware including use of the FreeSerifSoftware.com website and its services (the “Web Site”). FreeSerifSoftware knows how much you care about the way your Personal Data is used. We are committed to protecting the integrity and confidentiality of your information and act in a careful, sensible manner in compliance with the Data Protection Act 1998. We appreciate the trust you place in us.

Personal Data does not include information such as data, messages, text, graphics, images, photos, video, sounds, profiles, works of authorship and any other materials that has been posted on to the FreeSerifSoftware.com web site. The use of this information is detailed in our _Terms and Conditions_.

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. When we do we will update the “Last Updated” date and for material changes we will notify you by placing a notice on the home page of our Web Site for a minimum of seven days. It is therefore important that you regularly review this privacy policy to ensure you are updated as to any changes.

Who controls the Personal Data that is collected?  
How do we collect Personal Data?  
What Is Personal Data used for?  
Do we share Personal Data?  
What is a Cookie?  
How can you gain access to your Personal Data?  
How secure is your Personal Data?  
Do we transfer Personal Data overseas?  
Do we monitor and/or record communications?  
Contact Information

## Who Controls The Personal Information Collected? 

All Personal Data collected is in the control of FreeSerifSoftware. In the event that FreeSerifSoftware, its parent company or trading names and brands were subject to a change of ownership, the control and permissions that you have granted us with regard to your Personal Data will be transferred to the new owner.

## How Do We Collect Your Personal Information?

The Personal Data we collect is essential in helping us to provide an excellent overall experience for our customers when working with FreeSerifSoftware and for helping us to continually improve that experience.

There are several types of personal information we collect:

  * When you visit our Web Site, we use cookies (see below) to collect usage information and information about your computer and internet connection, including your computer's IP address, the type and version of browser and operating system you use, your internet domain and, if you arrived at our Web Site via a link from another website, the referring URL.  

  * When you become a member of our Web Site, a profile is created which will include Personal Data and preferences such as your desire to receive marketing communications from us.  

  * When you place an order with us, we will request all the Personal Data required to process the order including personal contact information and preferences such as your desire to receive marketing communications from us.   

  * Assuming you have consented to receiving marketing communications, we will use “image tracking” to ascertain whether you do or do not read our emailed marketing messages. It is worth remembering that all our marketing messages include full information on how to unsubscribe (stop receiving) future messages.   

In addition to the above, Google, as a third party vendor we work with, uses cookies to serve ads on our web site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to you based on your visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the _Google ad and content network privacy policy_. 

## What Is Your Personal Information Used For? 

We use Personal Data in four main ways: 

  * To allow log-in and full access to our Web Site in order for you to keep the Personal Data in your profile up to date and to personalise your Web Site experience.  

  * Assuming you have consented to receiving marketing communications, to notify you of new products, special offers, updated information and news.   

  * To enhance our order processing system with tools such order confirmation emails, product despatch notification and to make contact in the case of any difficulty.   

  * To generally help us improve the FreeSerifSoftware experience for you and others. 

## **Do we share Personal Data?**

We will not share your Personal Data with third parties without having obtained your permission. We will only disclose your personal information, without your permission or notice, if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: 

  * Conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on us.
  * Protect and defend our lawful rights and property.
  * Act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of our customers and the public.

## **What is a Cookie?**

A cookie is a small text file which is placed on to your computer via your web browser when you visit websites. Cookies are used to save certain information that you have entered into your computer, such as your name, as well as recording information such as the last time you visited a website or how you browsed to a website. Our use of cookies enables us to enhance your future visits with things such as personalised greetings, showing you content that you have shown interest in previously or for gathering statistical information such as what browser users are using. Cookies are only used by us to store data. They are not used to do anything harmful including things such as starting a process or programs on your computer or infecting your computer in any way.

If you choose to delete our cookies or set your internet browser to not accept cookies from us, you will still be able to view our Web Site. However you will not experience a personalised visit or be able to benefit from other personalised features.

## How Can You Gain Access To Personal Data? 

You can access your user information by accessing your profile through the log-in process of our Web Site. You can use your profile to access your orders information, keep your personal information up to date and to set what marketing communications you wish to receive.   
You can request and obtain details of the Personal Data we may hold about you by writing to:

Data Protection Manager  
FreeSerifSoftware  
12 Wilford Ind Est  
Nottingham  
NG11 7EP

Please quote your name and address together with your Customer ID. We would be grateful if you could also provide brief details of the information required as this will help us to accurately respond to your request. 

For the protection of all our customers, we will take all reasonable steps to confirm your identity before providing you with details of any Personal Data we may hold about you and we will aim to respond to such requests within 20 working days. 

## How Secure Is Your Personal Data?

We recognise that people are increasingly concerned about the protection of Personal Data from misuse and abuse, and about privacy in general. We constantly review and enhance our technical, physical and managerial procedures in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of Personal Data in order to protect it from unauthorised access, accidental loss and/or destruction.

We use industry standard 128 bit secure sockets layer (SSL) technology to encrypt sensitive information such as your credit card and other financial information.

It is important for you to remember to protect yourself against unauthorised access by guarding your password. For example, if you use a shared PC, make sure you logout or close your browser whenever you leave the PC.

## Do We Transfer Personal Data Overseas?

The Internet is a global environment. Using the Internet to collect and process Personal Data involves the transmission of data on an international basis. By browsing our Web Site and communicating with us you acknowledge and agree that your Personal Data may be transferred overseas but only to the minimum extent necessary and only in accordance with the other terms of this privacy policy. 

## **Do we monitor and/or record communications?**

Monitoring or recording of phone calls, e-mails, and other communications may take place in accordance with applicable law, and in particular for business purposes, such as for quality control and training, and in order to prevent or detect crime. Please visit the following websites for further information:  

## Contact Information 

FreeSerifSoftware welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy policy. Please contact us via our [Contact Us](http://support.serif.com/) page.

**FreeSerifSoftware.com**
